

Md. Tausif Rashid

Detail-oriented HR professional with strong interpersonal skills and 3 years of experience. Interested in building a career in a reputed organization. Adamant to work for the mutual growth of own career as well as for the growth of the organization with merit and endeavor.

Flat #DI, House #552, Nayatola, Moghbazar, Dhaka-1217, Bangladesh.

+8801790899501



tausif.rashid139@gmail.com



https://bd.linkedin.com/in/tausif-rashid-599599134

Talen Acquisition Executive at ZXY International

May 2019 - Present

- Being actively involved in end-to-end recruitment process by collecting manpower requisition with approval, posting job advertisements through job portals, CV screening, holding phone interviews, sending invitations and managing the hiring process;
- Passively sourcing quality candidates from online platforms and internal & external references
- Conducting & completing reference checking of selected candidates
- Communicating concern teams (Finance, IT, Transport & Admin) regarding new joiners joining information for smooth operation
- Conducting joining formalities (Paperwork) during the onboarding program
- Conducting building orientation of new joiners
- Maintaining CV Bank & follow up as & when any recruitment process starts to find suitable candidates



Experience

Executive, HR at iPay Systems Ltd.

July 2018 - April 2019

- Supporting the development and implementation of HR initiatives and systems;
- Being actively involved in recruitment by collecting manpower requisition with approval, posting
 job advertisements through job portals, CV screening, holding phone interviews, sending
 invitations and managing the hiring process;
- Preparing selection evaluation reports, ensuring approval of respective heads and finally taking approval of relevant management;
- Managing & maintaining recruitment files and keeping documentation maintaining the SOP;
- Providing job offer letter & ensuring scheduled employee on-boarding;
- Collecting & ensuring required joining documents;
- Maintaining employee records, (attendance, EEO records, etc), personal file according to policy;
- Assisting in performance management process;
- Supporting the management of disciplinary and grievance issues;

Junior HR Manager at ME SOLshare Ltd.

July 2017 - July 2018

Intern at Talent Centric Limited

January 2017 - March 2017



Education









Training on HRIS

- -Online Assessment Software for Recruitment
- -Web-based integrated human resource (HR) solution

Master of Professional Human Resource Management (MPHRM)

University of Dhaka 3.50 (On the scale of 4.00) January 2018 - Present

Bachelor of Business Administration (B.B.A)

North South University Human Resource Management 3.12 (On the scale of 4.00) January 2013 - April 2017

Notre Dame College, Dhaka **Business Studies** 5.00 (On the scale of 5.00)

Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC), 2012 Secondary School Certificate (SSC), 2010

Motijheel Govt. Boys' High School **Business Studies** 5.00 (On the scale of 5.00)

- Language: Excellent in reading, writing and speaking in both Bengali and English with exuberant communication skills.
 - Basic communication skill in Chinese language.
- □ Computer Literacy: 📲 MS Word 🗹 😰 PowerPoint 🗹 🖈 Excel 🗹
- Leadership: Built an HR department from scratch and maintained its operation in a startup company. Successfully lead a group in the business simulation called Haat Bazar at North South University. Was the project manager in 42 group projects in 42 different courses.
- Recruiting: Learned how to source & screen resumes for various job positions.

Member of North South University Earth Club, Fall 2013- Spring 2014.

Helped organize the climate simulation program called "Encounter" which is a 3D exhibition hosted annually with the portrayal of a different environmental theme.

- Member of Notre Dame College Cultural Club (NDCCC), 2010-2012.
- Participated in various programs of NDCCC, 2010 to 2012.
- Have a personal interest in playing guitar.
- Participated in the business simulation called Haat Bazar, Fall 2016.
- Nationality: Bangladeshi by birth.

Anindita Trisha

Lead - HR, Career management & Innovation

Total Bangladesh

anindita.trisha07@gmail.com (880) 1675188840

Daniel Ciganovic

Director - Business Development ME SOLshare Ltd.

daniel.ciganovic@me-solshare.com (880) 1709 275350 (49) 176 20994013